Shubham Gulati

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER • CERTIFIED CLOUD ARCHITECT

<u>linkedin.com/in/iamshgulati</u> • <u>shubhamgulati.com</u>

Shubham is an award-winning Senior Software Engineer with 7 years of exceptional IT experience at industry leading U.S. and Canadian professional services firms. He has a masters degree in Computer Science & Engineering and is certified in AWS cloud. His core competencies include web application development using Java, Spring Boot, and Microservices.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Technology Consultant - Deloitte Consulting, India

Jun 2022 - Nov 2022

- Lead a team of six junior developers to enhance the reliability and accuracy of a usage reporting application by 30%.
- Streamlined the development processes by enforcing best practices to improve code quality and reliability of the system.
- Reduced the risk of security incidents by designing a framework to access sensitive application data from a vault.

Technology Consultant - Deloitte Consulting, India

Sep 2019 - May 2022

- Developed the client's support portal which is a one stop shop for all the support related needs for business users.
- Increased code reusability and system reliability by developing a common foundation for all microservice modules.
- Improved the performance of mission-critical features by 25% by optimizing application code and database queries.

Technology Analyst - Deloitte Consulting, India

Apr 2018 – Aug 2019

- Developed a client's HR Portal which was a regulated product with highly sensitive data and numerical operations.
- Reduced the operational costs of the portal by 20% by re-writing the legacy Coldfusion application using Spring Boot.
- Improved the efficiency and security of the modules by up to 80% by re-architecting backend services for the cloud.

Associate Software Engineer - CGI Inc., India

Aug 2016 - Apr 2018

- Developed a framework to manage the state of system services which reduced the maintenance downtime by 95%.
- Migrated SOAP web services in legacy applications to REST endpoints using modern Spring Boot-based microservices.

EDUCATION

Master of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information TechnologyIndiaBachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information TechnologyIndiaPostgraduate Certificate, Cloud Computing & Blockchain, Saskatchewan PolytechnicSaskatoon, SKPostgraduate Certificate, Computer Application Security, Conestoga CollegeWaterloo, ON

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Developer Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Expected

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

FPDELC1KXFF1QXK5

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

JJMV6422RJ101NWV

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced Java, Microservices, Spring Boot, JPA, Hibernate, REST API, GraphQL, Git, GitHub, Postman, AWS

Intermediate SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Swagger, OpenAPI, GCP, OAuth, CrushFTP, Next.js, TailwindCSS

Basics Shell Scripting, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Solidity, Ethereum, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React

REWARDS & RECOGNITION

Nov 2023	Dean's List Award, Outstanding academic performance in Cloud Computing & Blockchain	Saskpoly
Mar 2022	Applause Award, Technical contribution to the success of the eCX project	Deloitte
Dec 2020	Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the STAR Migration project	Deloitte
Jul 2019	Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the HRAlly project	Deloitte
Feb 2019	Applause Award, Project delivery excellence during the development of the HRAlly project	Deloitte
Jan 2019	Spot Award , Critical support during CSP 2.0 project go-live	Deloitte
Dec 2018	Applause Award, Delivery excellence during CSP 2.0 project development	Deloitte
Sep 2017	Apex Award, Unsupervised delivery, and individual contribution to the M2M GDSP project	CGI

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Portfolio – Self-taught Next.js, React, and TailwindCSS to develop a personal website with minimal and modern design.

Emoverse – Full-stack journaling platform built using AWS serverless services, and fully automated CI-CD pipeline.

Smart Degrees – DApp to issue digital certificates built using Solidity, Web3 libraries, and Ethereum blockchain.

<u>DevMyMacX</u>, **<u>DevMyLinuX</u>** – Self-taught shell scripting to create a bootstrap scripts to setup macOS & Arch Linux.

PUBLICATIONS

An efficient technique to control road traffic using Fuzzy Neural Network System

Research Paper, Published in IEEE Journal - https://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICRITO.2014.7014723